Tyler Nguyen

www.tylerthecoder.com • 206.412.8332 • tynguyen06@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-nguyen • github.com/tylern06

WEB DEVELOPER

Technically driven web developer with experience building websites for a diverse range of clients. Experience in bringing design mockups to working user interfaces using Javascript, HTML5, CSS3 and AngularJS. Inspired by emerging technologies as well as motivated by challenging projects and deadlines.

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

Front-End Development: HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Sass, HTTP Request/Response, AJAX, JSON, XML, Responsive Design

Languages: JavaScript (ES5/ES6), Ruby, Python

Databases: SQL(MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js

Version Control: Git, Github, Bitbucket, Tower

Servers: Apache, Node.js, Nginx

Frameworks: Angular S, Vue, React, Express, Ruby on Rails, Flask, Twitter Bootstrap,

CMS: Wordpress

Task Runners: Gulp, Webpack

Methodologies: OOP - Object Oriented Programming, MVC, RESTful Architecture, Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Conflare | Seattle, Washington (10/2016 - Current)

Web Developer

Developed websites based on mockups from Adobe Illustrator and InVision to create responsive web sites using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Sass.

- Worked closely with design team and project managers on various projects by building out pixel perfect and responsive sites.
- Built out multiple client websites using HTML, CSS(Sass), Javascript, and Bootstrap.
- Increased development workflow by implementing Gulp task runner to compile, minifies, and cache bust asset files.
- Debug and resolved front end issues using Chrome browser inspector tool.
- Implemented client side validations for forms using AJAX
- Tested cross browser functionality and responsiveness using BrowserStack.
- Clients include:
 - o Douglas Smith, douglassmith.info
 - o Rogoway Law, rogowaylaw.com
 - o Lafarge & Egge, lafargeandegge.com
 - o Willis Eckfeldt
 - o TMaicee Photography

Samsung Electronics America | Bellevue, Washington (2/2012 – 2/2016)

Test Engineer II

Responsible for test planning and cross team operational project management within the T-Mobile and AT&T Samsung mobile devices

- Worked closely with hardware and software development teams in Korea Headquarters to raise and verify issues on mobile devices (raised 400+ device issues on PLM bug tracking system).
- Performed interoperability tests on different vendor networks to test the functionality and performance of smartphones.
- Created test plans and test procedures for software testing and hardware performance testing to verify product quality.
- Conducted field drive tests to verify RF and protocol performance; call drop, data throughput, and RAT handover.
- Validated GPS stationary and driving performance using test automation tools.
- Detected and managed critical issues in a timely manner to increase Samsung mobile device's quality and stability in a rapidly progressing mobile industry.

RPM Systems | Redmond, Washington (4/2011 – 6/2011)

Electrical Engineer Intern

Responsible for designing a battery operated switch mode power for field test applications.

- Simulated a voltage mode and current mode feedback control circuit design using LTSPICE.
- Designed a current limiting feature for a power supply to protect circuit from a potential short
- Assisted in the technical, cost, and risk considerations of a portable power supply.
- Implemented a PCB layout of battery switch mode power supply using a 4-layer PCB board
- Reported design process and calculations into a documentation report.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Completed an intensive web development program at Coding Dojo starting in February 2016, with over 1000 hours of coding. Achieved a double black belt, by developing a web app from wireframe to deploying the app in under 4.5 hours.

Grand Catch (MEAN) http://www.grandcatch.com

A web application that compares the prices of products from Amazon and eBay to help save shoppers money and increase their buying experience. Users can filter the products by categories and sort by lowest to highest prices. (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, AJAX)

Swept Away (Ruby on Rails) http://www.sweptaway.co

A web application that allows users to post chores that are displayed via Google Maps. Clients and contractors can each login into their respective accounts to view, edit, and accept their chores. (Ruby on Rails, SQLite, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, Google Maps API.)

The Movie Seeker (MEAN) http://www.themovieseeker.com

A movie application that implements several movie APIs to display movie showtimes, trailers, news, and reviews. It allows users to register, login, and leave movie reviews. (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, AJAX)

EDUCATION

Web Development Certificate

Coding Dojo | 6/2016

B.S. ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

University of Washington Bothell | 8/2011

Minor: Math

Dean's List: Summer '08, Winter '10, Spring '10